Matthew B. Bowler

1210 North 16th Street Jacksonville Beach, Florida 32250 Phone: 904–351-8487 Email: mbowler03@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am an organized and dedicated finance and sales professional with a successful track record of implementing and completing projects. Currently, I am in the process of becoming a "full stack developer" in order to merge my current finance skills and experience with new and emerging technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Owner, North Florida Healthy Vending

2018 to Present

 Owner of several healthy vending machines located in various private and charter schools in Jacksonville, Florida...

Loan Officer, BBVA Compass Bank

2018 to 2019

• Loan Officer to four BBVA locations in Jacksonville, Florida

Senior Loan Officer, Carrington Mortgage Jacksonville, Florida

2015 to 2018

- Closed over 23 million in FHA and VA mortgages in 2016 becoming one of the companies leading producers
- Obtained the promotion of "Senior Loan Officer" during the first month of eligibility by closing an average of over 14 loans per month since date of hire
- Obtained and currently hold thirty-two originators licenses

Account Manager, XPO Logistics Jacksonville, Florida

2013 to 2015

- Specialized in the management of the transportation needs of large retail clients
- Solicited new business obtained from paid sales leads, research, social media, and referrals

Loan Originator, PHH Mortgage Jacksonville, FL

2011 to 2013

- Originated Mortgage Loans under Private Label Solutions for a variety of companies including: Charles Schwab, Merrill Lynch, E*Trade, TIAA-Cref, Ameriprise, and Keybank
- Participated in federal refinance program called HARP which includes but is not limited to effectively matching a variety of clients needs to the most beneficial product while adhering to continually changing regulations
- Obtained and held twenty-two originators licenses

Executive Director, Riverside Avondale Development Organization 2006 to 2011 Jacksonville, FL

- Supervised all business activities, including staff, finances, production, marketing and sales
- Provided oversight of internal and external audits and applicable governmental filings
- Secured a minimum of \$125,000 per year in grants and donations annually
- Increased housing production by 300%, expanded service boundaries, and conducted all predevelopment activities for two future signature projects
- Served as a leader in the implementation of processes under the federal Neighborhood Stabilization Program
- Initiated a new internal marketing strategy to include a comprehensive website, annual fundraiser, electronic
- and direct mail newsletter, an annual report, and an upgrade of all existing marketing materials
- Implemented a green initiative for all new projects in order to adhere to Florida Green Building Standards
- Strengthened a volunteer board of directors by recruiting and training new leaders from the local community

Vice President, Operation New Hope Jacksonville, FL

2000-2006

- Conducted research and repair of property titles including removal and payment of liens and assessed taxes
- Purchased more than sixty properties in the downtown Jacksonville area through grants and lines of credit
- Determined project feasibility by input and analysis of budgets, subcontractor bids, and subsidy availability
- Analyzed budgets to determine accurate revenue and expenditures and projected cash flow
- Assisted in raising funds for the organization through grant writing and tax credit submissions
- Sold and marketed all existing housing inventory
- Collaborated with a board of directors on a continual basis

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida (Online)

• 24 Week Coding BootCamp- Currently enrolled

University of North Florida Jacksonville, FL

Bachelor's Degree of Business Administration- Business Management